Chicago & Northwestern Transportation Company Records 5533
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series X: Minneapolis and St. Louis Railway. Local Agreements, Conferences, and Reports, 1926-1960
  - Report re Conference in re Tow Engine Crew Consist, Between M&St.L Railway and BLF&E, BLE., 1957-1958 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Possible violation of Article 45 of Agreement.
  - Hours of Service. Compensation for Crews., 1923-1924 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    For crews deadheading or being towed.
  - Mail, Express and Baggage, Handling of by Trainmen. Extra Compensation., 1925-1954 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Claims filed with Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen.
  - Piloting: Road. Use of Conductors., 1935-1956 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Special Trains. Crew Consist., 1924-1939 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Shop Crafts. Local Agreements, Operating rules. Violations and grievances. [Folder 1 of 2]., 1956-1960 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Agreement violations; consolidated code of operating rules; contracting out work; seniority; apprenticeships.
  - Shop Crafts. Local Agreements, Operating rules. Violations and grievances. [Folder 2 of 2]., 1956-1960 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Power of Attorney and Representation Authorization, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    BRT and BLF&E
  - Agreements, In re Five-Day Week., 1951-1955 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    With the ORC, BRT, and BLF&E.
  - Memorandum of Agreement to Operate Freight Train from Nemo and Monmouth, 1929-1946 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    With the ORC, BLE, BRT, and BLF&E.
  - Yard Layovers, 1926-1957 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    On trains from Nemo and Monmouth.
  - Railway Patrolmen. Agreements., 1944-1954 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    3 booklets. Also contains correspondence and circulars.
  - Featherbedding. Newspaper Clippings, Agreements, and Correspondence., 1956-1960 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    Includes articles on featherbedding, labor law, agreements with various classes of employees, and correspondence.
  - Use of Edifone Equipment to Record Formal Investigations, 1956-1960 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    Folder includes a "test recording" on an Ediphone Diamond Disc.
- Series XI: Clerks, Represented by the Brotherhood of Railway, Airline and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express and Station Employees [BRAC], 1921-1960
  This series consists of records of labor relations between the M&St.L and the BRAC locals that represented their employees. Contained in this series are claims from employees, reports on conference between local representatives and management, implementation of agreements, correspondence, and conferences regarding the abolishment of positions that have been made redundant by automated processes.
  - Item 12 on Docket: Inventory Accountant matter., 1956-1958 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    Memoranda and notes from conferences re rate of pay for Inventory Accountant position. Between carriers and Clerks.
  - Rate of Pay Adjustments in General Accounting Department, 1958-1960 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    Conference between carriers and Clerks.
  - Reports on Conferences with Clerks re Job Abolishment, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    With regard to decision reached in matter of conference between Boston & Maine Railroad and BRAC Clerks.
  - Clerk. H.J. Fairweather Seniority Status, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    August 25 1959. Filed by BRAC.
  - Reinstatement of Clerk, D.F. Jacobson, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    Reports on conference between carrier and BRAC.
  - Clerk. Alma E. Britting Resigning., 1959 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    Abolishment of her position; Dictaphone recording device replaces stenographer.
  - Displacement Rights of Clerks, 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    Stenographer pool employees.
  - Relocation of Certain Positions from Local Freight Office to General Office, 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    Report on conference with BRAC.
  - Abolishment of One Janitorial Position, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Force Reduction at Marshalltown Freight Station, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Clerks. Reinstatement of Martin Johnson., 1959 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    RESTRICTED. Contains Discipline File and Edison Dictaphone recording of investigation.
  - Clerks. Reinstatement of J.F. Walyka., 1959 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Handling and Progressing of Claims. BRAC correspondence., 1959 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    October 22, 1959
  - Clerks. Restoration to Furlough Status and Seniority Rights, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Clerks. General, 1924-1925 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Clerks. General [Folder 1 of 3], 1921-1924 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    Contains letter re practice of firing female employees if they get married.
  - Clerks. General [Folder 2 of 3], 1921-1924 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Clerks. General [Folder 3 of 3], 1921-1924 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Clerks. Schedules of Pay Rates., 1945 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Clerks. Force Reduction. E.G. Olson., 1957-1958 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    Discontinuance of position in revenue accounting division, and redistribution of wealth.
- Series XII: Yardmasters, Represented by Railroad Yardmasters of America [RRYMoA], 1922-1960
  This series consists of records of labor relations between the M&St.L and the RRYMoA locals that represented their employees. Contained in this series are claims from employees, reports on conference between local representatives and management, agreements, memoranda of understanding, correspondence, and conferences regarding how open positions are advertised on the boards. Of particular interest is the report of the Emergency Board on the implementation of the 40- Hour workweek.
  - Yardmasters Notice. Association of Western Railways, Circulars 759 Series., 1956-1958 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    Requesting increase of rate of pay.
  - Conferences in re Bulletins advertising for vacancies in yardwork., 1945-1951 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Yardmaster Wage Increase. Conference Report., 1958 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    With Railroad Yardmasters of America.
  - Yardmaster Wage Increase. Conference Report., 1959 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Yardmasters. Wage Claims, 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Yardmasters. Agreements. Revised Schedules and Rates of Pay., 1922-1927 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    Correspondence re negotiations contains coded telegraphs.
  - Yardmasters. Agreements. Rates of Pay and Working Conditions., 1935-1939 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Yardmasters. General., 1940-1944 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    Contains claims, correspondence, agreements, and rates of pay.
  - Yardmasters. Rates of Pay Increases and General Revision of Rules. Agreements and Mediation., 1945-1947 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    Includes "Report to the President by Emergency Board Appointed March 8, 1945," circulars, and correspondence.
  - Yardmasters. Agreements and Memorandum of Understanding., 1948-1951 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    Railroad Yardmasters of America.
  - Yardmasters. General., 1952 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    Contains Agreements with Railroad Yardmasters of America regarding seniority and policies for furloughed employees.
  - Yardmasters. General., 1953-1955 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Contains circulars, claims, correspondence, conference reports, and rates of pay.
  - Yardmasters. General., 1956-1959 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Includes circulars, Agreement for increase in rate of pay, correspondence, and claims.
  - Yardmasters. General., 1941-1950 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Includes circulars, correspondence, and Agreement.
  - Yardmasters. Emergency Board Decision on 40 Hour Work Week., 1951-1956 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Board decision from 1951, three pieces of correspondence relating to decision from 1956.
- Series XIII: Dispatchers, Represented by the American Train Dispatchers Association, 1921-1960
  This series consists of records of labor relations between the M&St.L and the ATDA locals that represented their employees. Contained in this series are claims from employees, reports on conference between local representatives and management, agreements, correspondence, and conferences regarding consolidation and abolishment of positions for dispatchers.
  - Dispatchers. Rates of Pay., 1923-1935 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Dispatchers. Extra Pay Claims., 1951-1953 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Dispatchers. Re-Instatement., 1953 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Dispatchers. Seniority., 1953-1960 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Dispatchers. Re-Assignment. Notices and Correspondence., 1960 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Dispatchers. Agreements., 1957 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    August 8 1957
  - Dispatchers. General., 1921-1925 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Dispatchers. General., 1926-1929 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Dispatchers. General., 1930-1935 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Dispatchers. General. Correspondence and Other Documents., 1936-1939 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Dispatchers. General., 1940 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Dispatchers. General., 1941 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Dispatchers. General. Agreement and Correspondence., 1942 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Dispatchers. General. Agreements and Correspondence., 1943-1946 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Dispatchers. General. Folder 1 of 3., 1947 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    Folder 1 of 3.
  - Dispatchers. General. National Mediation Board. Folder 2 of 3., 1947 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    Folder 2 of 3.
  - Dispatchers. General. Folder 3 of 3., 1947 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    Folder 3 of 3.
  - Dispatchers. General., 1948-1949 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Dispatchers. General. Correspondence and Circulars., 1950 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Dispatchers. General. Circulars and Agreement., 1951 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Dispatchers. General., 1952-1953 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Dispatchers. General., 1954 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Dispatchers. General. Agreement and Correspondence., 1955 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Dispatchers. General., 1956 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    Folder 1 of 2.
  - Dispatchers. General., 1956 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Folder 2 of 2.
  - Dispatchers. General., 1957 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Dispatchers. General., 1957 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Dispatchers. General., 1958-1960 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Series Series XIV: Agreements, Historic, Between Various Labor Organizations and Ft. Dodge, Des Moines, and Southern Railroad, 1907-1947
  This series consists of historic agreements between the Ft. Dodge, Des Moines, and Southern Railroad and various labor organizations representing their employees. These are a valuable resource for the study of the development of collective bargaining agreements between carriers and labor organizations.
  - Agreement, Memorandum of. Trainmen., 1907 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Agreement. Conductors and Brakemen., 1911 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    1 booklet.
  - Agreements. Motormen., 1911 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Agreements. Conductors., 1912 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Agreements. Linemen., 1912 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Agreements. Motormen., 1912 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Agreements. Trainmen., 1913 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    January 1 1913
  - Agreements. Conductors., 1914 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Agreements. Linemen., 1914 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    June 1 1914.
  - Agreements. Motormen., 1914 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Agreements. Trainmen., 1914 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Agreements. Linemen., 1915 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    June 1 1915
  - Agreements. Adamson law., 1916-1918 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    September 5 1916 - September 5 1918.
  - Agreements. Conductors., 1916 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Agreements. Linemen., 1916 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    June 1 1916.
  - Agreements. Motormen., 1916 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Agreements. Trainmen., 1916 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Agreements. Carmen., 1917 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Agreements. Conductors, Motormen, Trainmen., 1917 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    May 7 - 12 1917
  - Agreements. Linemen., 1917 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    June 14 1917
  - Agreements. Outside Electricians and Bonders., 1917 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Agreements. Power House., 1917 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Agreements. Shop Agreements., 1917 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Agreements. Steam Shovel., 1917 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    March 13 1917
  - Agreements. Substation Operators., 1917 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    June 14 1917.
  - Agreements. Conductors., 1918 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Agreements. Motormen., 1918 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Agreements. Trainmen., 1918 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Agreements. All trainmen., 1920 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    BLE, BRT, and ORC.
  - Agreements. Maintenance of Way., 1920 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Agreements. Power House., 1920 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Agreements. Blacksmiths., 1921 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Agreements. Carmen., 1921-1929 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Agreements. Interlocking Operators., 1928 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Agreements. Linkmen., 1921 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    January 1 1921.
  - Agreements. Machinists., 1921 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Agreements. Maintenance of Way., 1921 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Agreements. Outside Electricians and Bonders., 1921 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Agreements. Shop Electricians., 1921 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    January 1 1921
  - Agreements. Signalmen., 1921 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Agreements. Substation Operators., 1921 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Agreements. Blacksmiths., 1922 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Agreements. Carmen., 1922 (Box 10, Folder 49)
    June 1 1922.
  - Agreements. Electrical Maintainers and Bonders, 1922 (Box 10, Folder 50)
    June 1 1922
  - Agreements. Linemen and Ground men, 1922 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Agreements. Machinists., 1922 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Agreements. Maintenance of Way, 1922 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Agreements. Power House Employers., 1922 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Agreements. Shop Electricians., 1922 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Agreements. Signalmen., 1922 (Box 10, Folder 56)
    March 21 1922.
  - Agreements. Substation Operators., 1922 (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Agreements. Signalmen., 1923 (Box 10, Folder 58)
    July 21 to October 1 1923
  - Agreements. Shop Crafts, 1925 (Box 10, Folder 59)
    July 30 1925
  - Agreements. Bridge and Building Workers, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 60)
    December 1926
  - Agreements. Conductors, Motormen and Brakemen., 1927 (Box 10, Folder 61)
    February to August 9 1927
  - Agreements. Emergency Men., 1927 (Box 10, Folder 62)
    February 23 to November 25 1927
  - Agreements. Conductor., 1929 (Box 10, Folder 63)
    August 17 1929
  - Agreements. Power House Employees, 1929 (Box 10, Folder 64)
    February to June 10 1929
  - Agreements. Conductors and Motormen, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 65)
    March to April 1930.
  - Agreements. Blacksmiths, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 66)
    February 11 1932
  - Agreements. Carmen., 1932 (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - Agreements. Conductors, Motormen and Trainmen, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 68)
    February 23 1932
  - Agreements. Electrical Maintainers and Bonders., 1932 (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - Agreements. Linemen., 1932 (Box 10, Folder 70)
    February 10 1932
  - Agreements. Machinists., 1932 (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - Agreements. Power House Employees, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 72)
    February 1932
  - Agreements. Shop Electricians., 1932 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - Agreements. Signalmen., 1932 (Box 10, Folder 74)
    February 1932.
  - Agreements. Substation Operators., 1932 (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - Agreements. Conductors, Motormen and Trainmen, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 76)
    September to November 1933
  - Agreements. Substation Operators, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 77)
    September to October 1933
  - Agreements. Conductors, Motormen and Trainmen, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 78)
    August 23 1935
  - Agreements. Electrical Maintainers and Bonders, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 79)
    February 9 1935
  - Agreements. Machinists, 1941 (Box 10, Folder 80)
    September 6 1941
  - Agreements. Power House Employees, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 81)
    March 1942
  - Agreements. Power House Employees, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 82)
    August 16 1944
  - Agreements. Railway Supervisors, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 83)
    August 1 1944. 2 booklets.
  - Agreements. Machinists., 1945 (Box 10, Folder 84)
    April 28 1945
  - Agreements. Power House Employees., 1942-1945 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Agreements. Clerks., 1946 (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - Agreements. Conductors., 1946 (Box 10, Folder 87)
    August 30 1946
  - Agreements. Maintenance of Way., 1946 (Box 10, Folder 88)
    June 1 1946
  - Agreements. Trainmen, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 89)
  - Agreements. Shop Crafts, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 90)
    September 21 1946
  - Agreements. Clerks, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 91)
    February 3 1947